# Oscar Castillejo

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oscar-castillejo/ Github: https://github.com/oacs

## **Summary**

Senior Software Developer (5+ years) with a strong background in Web Development using technologies such as Typescript, React.js, and AWS Serverless services. Recognized 9 times for outstanding performance. Founding software engineer at fin-tech startup, contributed to raising \$1 million in Series A seed funding and promptly addressed client-facing issues

### Skills

- Languages: Typescript, Javascript, SQL, NoSQL, GraphQL, Java, Go, SCSS, CSS3
- Framework & Libraries: Express.js, Node.js, React.js (Redux), Vue.js (Vuex), TailwindCSS, Apollo, Rxjs, Jest, Cypress
- Tools: AWS (RDS, DynamoDB, Api Gateway, SQS, Lamda, S3, CloudWatch), Git, Docker, Webpack, Jira, Figma, PostgreSQL

## **Experience**

#### Software Engineer Technical Lead | Finastra

May 2022 - Feb 2023

Email: oscar.castillejo.sa@gmail.com

Mobile: +1-647-615-3226

Stack: Vue.js, Vuex, SCSS, Typescript, AWS Serverless Services, Node.js, SQL, GraphQL, Express.js, Java, CircleCl

Mississauga, CA

- Led an international team of 10 developers to disrupt the Canadian mortgage industry taking care of code reviews, splitting efforts, design improvements and promoting high-quality code
- Directed the release process with live support of 7 major features for the Expert Pro product and more than 20 hotfixes and small enhancements
- Redesigned key workflows in collaboration with product owners based on their requirements, resulting in a 25% increase in productivity measured by a reduction in time to completion and an improved user experience
- Designed and Directed the development internship program by interviewing potential candidates; leading a team of interns to improve a web client, API, infrastructure and CI/CD; and work with project managers and stakeholders to ensure timely delivery
- Awarded 9 times within the organization for innovation, leading the team to success, outstanding performance and manage to solve critical situations on vacations

#### Founding Software Engineer | Doorr (acquired by Finastra)

Aug 2020 - May 2022

Stack: Vue.is, Vuex, SCSS, Typescript, AWS Serverless Services, Node.is, SQL, GraphQL, Express.is, Java, CircleCl

Mississauga, CA

- Ensured dependencies and libraries were compatible and up to date with latest releases avoiding more than 120 vulnerabilities on the products
- One of three Back-end engineer at a startup that raised \$1 million in Series A seed funding design the foundations of core features such as CRM, Automations, External API, Websockets for real time updates and (i18n) solution on a full-stack perspective using AWS Serverless solution and always bringing ideas on how to improve all the process on the company
- Increased customers satisfaction by promptly addressing client-faced issues reported by the Customer Success team with quick response times and effective solutions

#### Frontend Developer | Telesero

Aug 2019 - Mar 2020

Stack: React.js, Redux, Rxjs, SCSS, Styled components, Figma

United States

- Migrated legacy code to technologies such as React, Redux, improving the performance of the system with lower response time from 5 seconds to 1 second of load time
- Revamped the look and feel of the company's products following the Material Design Patterns using Styled components, resulting in overall better UI/UX and improved user satisfaction by 90% with the implementation of intuitive navigation and better visual design elements
- Designed a Dashboard and Monitor web app from scratch with real-time updates using Websocket and Rxjs, enhancing data representation by the implementation of interactive charts and graphs

#### Mobile Developer - Freelance | NextLine

Jul 2020 - Dec 2020

Stack: Flutter, Dart, Django, Python

Venezuela

• Design and developed a mobile app to manage the services provided by the company integrating customer support chats, scheduled repair appointments, changing plans and manage payment

#### **Education**

**Bachelor of Computer Science** 

Aug 2014 - Sep 2020 Guayana, VE